我在飓风上结婚怎么样
What if we got married on the cyclone?
科尼岛的过山车吗
The roller coaster at Coney Island?
想想啊  那得多好玩
Come on. How much fun would that be?
而且你说这多合适啊
And talk about an appropriate,
虽然这暗喻的意思有点明显
if not slightly on-the-nose metaphor...
新娘新郎肩并肩
a bride and groom together, side-by-side,
经历人生中的起起伏伏
as they go through the ups and downs,
辗转波折  和周而复始
the twists and turns, and the loop-de-loops of life.
卡塞尔我爱你
Castle, I love you,
但我不会在车上  太空
but I will not marry you on a ride
或过山车上跟你结婚
or up in space or on a slide.
苏斯博士肯定在个很有趣的地方结的婚
Bet Dr. Seuss got married somewhere fun.
是啊  在他妻子的客厅里
Yes, his wife's living room.
而且那种过山车上
How many people do you think can fit
能塞下多少人啊
in one of those roller-coaster cars, anyway?
二三十吗
20? 30?
说得对
You know, that's a good point.
我们该决定好我们该请谁
We should determine exactly whom we are going to invite.
是啊  好主意
Yeah, good idea.
这样我们就能决定该建造一个
That way we can determine exactly how big
多大的过山车了
a roller-coaster car we need to build.
或者我们需要一个多大的实际场地
Or how big of an actual venue we need.
不管怎样  我去拿纸
Either way, I'll go and get the paper.
我去拿笔
I'll get a pen.
我还是接电话吧
And I will get the phone.
要知道  少请点人是很有道理的
You know, there's a good argument for keeping the list really small.
比如只请近亲
Just immediate family.
你的道理跟某种
This argument doesn't have something to do with
游乐园器械无关吧
a certain amusement park ride, does it?
我是认真的
I'm being serious.
结婚是件私密的事
Getting married is an intimate act,
我们的仪式应该也很有私密感
and our ceremony should reflect that intimacy.
而且这样  我们都能坐进过山车里了
And that way, we could all fit into one car.
莱恩  你对过山车什么意见
Ryan, how do you feel about roller coasters?
让我想吐  怎么了
Ooh, make me nauseous. Why?
没什么  死者是谁
No reason. Who's our victim?
彼得·科尔德罗  26岁
Peter Cordero, 26.
据楼管说  他是独居
According to the super, he lives alone.
是哈丁集团的期货交易员
He's a future's trader at JP Harding,
是华尔街的投资公司
the Wall Street investment firm.
他怎么死的
And how was he killed?
胸口中一枪致死
Uh, single GSW to the chest.
看来他的未来[期货]被卖掉了
Looks like his own future got traded.
而且还拼死挣扎了一番
Yeah, not without a fight first.
谁发现了尸体
Who found the body?
这个问题很有趣
Well, that's an interesting question.
晚上10点3分  一个女人拨打911
At 10:03 p.m., a woman made a 911 call
电话是从街区前边一部付费电话打出
from a pay phone down the block,
但她没说名字
but she refused to leave her name.
街区前边的一部付费电话
A pay phone down the block?
那她怎么知道他死了呢  除非...
But how would she know he was dead unless...
除非她进过公寓
Unless she was in the apartment.
从尸斑来看  死亡时间
Well, lividity places the time of death
在8点到10点之间
8:00 and 10:00,
如果911电话是10点3分拨出
So if the 911 call came in at 10:03...
她可能就是凶手
She could be our killer.
埃斯波西托在检查监控录像
Esposito's checking security-cam footage.
希望能拍到她
Hopefully, we caught her on tape.
只有我觉得奇怪吗
Now, is it just me, or is it odd
死者穿着西装外套  打领带  裤子
that our victim is wearing a suit jacket, tie, pants,
鞋子  却唯有衬衫解开了
shoes, but his shirt is unbuttoned?
的确挺怪  还有这个
It's odd, all right. And look at this...
他被射杀时  他的衬衫是穿好扣好的
His shirt was on and buttoned when he was shot.
那么凶手是在他死后解开衬衫的
So our killer unbuttoned his shirt after he was dead.
是的
Yep.
凶手在找什么
The killer was looking for something.
价值连城的项链  或者像《华尔街之狼》那样
A pricy necklace or... oh, a bunch of cash
找贴在他胸前的一堆现金
taped to his chest like "Wolf of Wall Street."
还有别的
There's something else.
我完全找不到自卫伤
I didn't find any defensive wounds,
如果他们在那边发生了打斗
So if there was a fight out there,
估计他是没参与
I don't think this guy was in it.
贝克特
Yo, Beckett.
大堂没有监控摄像头
There are no security cameras in the lobby,
但街上一家酒肆有摄像头
but I found one in a liquor store down the street.
拍到了911电话打进来时付费电话那里的照片
It got a shot of that pay phone right when the 911 call came in.
在邻里排查
Okay. Canvas the neighbors.
看是否有人在楼里看到过她
See if anyone saw her in the building.
你们找到近亲了吗
Did you talk to next of kin yet?
他没有很近的亲属
Well, the guy didn't have any immediate family,
但他在皇后区有个堂亲
But he did list a cousin in Queens,
玛利亚·科尔德罗  是他的紧急联系人
a Maria Cordero, as his in-case-of-emergency.
好的  去带她来局里
All right, bring her in.
看她是否认得照片里的女人
Let's see if she recognizes the woman in the photo.
我和卡塞尔去他工作的地方
Castle and I will go to his place of work
看看他们知道什么
and see what they know there.
好的
All right.
抱歉  我不认识她
No. No. I'm sorry. I don't know her.
玛利亚  你堂哥有没有提过他有女朋友
Maria, did your cousin say anything about having a girlfriend?
没有  他说他没时间  工作是他的全部
No. He said he didn't have time. Work was his life.
你们很亲密吗
Were the two of you close?
彼得就像我哥哥一样
Peter was like my brother.
他10岁时  他父母死于委内瑞拉的一场大地震
When he was 10, his parents died in the big earthquake in Venezuela.
我父母领养了他  把他带来美国
My parents adopted him and brought him to the states.
彼得有提过他有什么仇家吗
Did Peter say anything about having any enemies?
没有  他人很好
No. Peter was a sweet guy.
他从未忘记自己的出身
He never forgot where he came from...
不像他工作上那些生于富贵人家的人
Not like those privileged, silver-spoon types he worked with.
他是个拿奖学金的孩子
He was a scholarship kid,
他得到的一切都是靠努力工作
so everything he got was through hard work.
你最后一次跟他说话是什么时候
When did you talk to him last?
几天前
A few days ago.
他精神如何
And how did he seem?
压力很大的样子
Stressed, actually.
他说是什么事了吗
Did he say what about?
没有  我不知道
No. I-I don't know.
我问他时  他只说是工作上的事
When I asked him, he said something happened at work,
不过他应付得来
but it wasn't anything he couldn't handle.
哈丁集团投资银行
JP Harding investment bank.
这里要么是资本主义的动力
This place is either the engine of capitalism
要么是贪婪和腐败的代表
or the poster child of greed and corruption,
这要看你读哪份报纸了
depending on which paper you read.
或许是市场的无形之手杀了彼得
Maybe the invisible hand of the market killed Peter.
这就能解释他为什么没有自卫伤了
It would explain the lack of defensive wounds.
我预科学校的一个同学离开大学后来这儿工作
You know, prep-school buddy of mine came to work here out of college.
他不到30就挣了2.5亿
He made a quarter of a billion dollars before he was 30,
然后退休  买了座小岛
retired, and bought an island.
什么  他有自己的小岛
Wait. He owns his own island?
我们应该请他来参加婚礼
We should definitely invite him to the wedding.
你好  我是贝克特探长
Excuse me. Hi, I'm detective Beckett.
我们要见彼得·科尔德罗的上司
We need to speak with Peter Cordero's boss.
是杰米·波曼吧
Jamie Berman, I believe?
我能告诉他是关于什么事的吗
Can I tell him what it's regarding?
猎杀
Killing --
你们有这个本事吗
are you capable of it?
如果你们有  我能让你们发大财
Because if you are, I will make you rich.
高盛今早刚从我们这里挖走了
Goldman just poached consolidated's pension account
集团的养老金账户  所以我现在悬赏
from us this morning, so I am offering a bounty.
尼尔
Neal?
一百万美金  给在座之中第一个
A million dollars to the first son of a bitch at this table
从高盛那里把客户挖回来的人
to poach an account back from Goldman.
狩猎季节到了  各位  狩猎季节
It's open season, guys -- open-hunting season.
我要你们把他们杀得血肉横飞
I want you to make them bleed!
打扰一下
Excuse me.
好了  上吧
All right, let's go!
打扰一下  波曼先生
Excuse me, Mr. Berman.
贝克特探长  能说几句吗
Detective Beckett. Could we have a word, please?
你们这些证监会找茬的去跟我律师谈
I told you S.E.C. pricks to talk to my lawyer.
我不是证监会的  是纽约警局的  凶案组
I'm not S.E.C. I'm NYPD -- homicide.
凶案组
Homicide?
刚刚那出戏抱歉了  探长
I apologize for the theatrics, detective,
但在这个世界  钱能激励他们
but in this world, it gets results.
我还以为
And here I thought the stories
那些华尔街故事太夸张了呢
of wall street excess were exaggerated.
波曼先生  据我所知彼得·科尔德罗
Mr. Berman, I understand that Peter Cordero
是你的直属下属
reported directly to you.
对  他是我手下最好的期货操盘手
Yes, he was my best commodities' trader.
是我见过的最好的人
And one of the nicest guys you'll ever meet.
至少是在这个圈子里
In this part of the world, anyway.
你们有什么线索了吗
Do you have any leads?
只有一个
Uh, just one.
你认识这个女人吗
Do you recognize this woman?
不  不认识
No. I'm afraid I don't.
据彼得·科尔德罗的家人说
Well, according to Peter Cordero's family,
他在工作上遇到了麻烦
he was having some trouble here at work.
你知道可能是什么事吗
Do you have any idea what that might have been?
不知道
No idea.
其实  他本月业绩是最好的一个月
In fact, he was having one of the best months he's ever had.
那他的客户呢  有什么问题吗
And what about his clients? Any problems there?
他是明日之星  客户们都喜欢他
Well, Pete was a rising star. His clients loved him...
但是
But...
但是什么
But what?
上周  我走楼梯上65楼
Last week, I was taking the stairs to the 65th floor --
我的锻炼方式
my version of exercise --
我看到彼得在楼梯间里
and I saw Peter in the stairwell
跟一个看着像小混混的人在一起
with this guy who looked like a gangbanger.
脖子上都是纹身  脸上有大刀疤
All tatted up his neck, big scar on his cheek.
是在这里不会看到的那种人
Not the kind of guy you ever see down here.
他给了彼得一个这么大的包裹
And he was handing Peter a package about yea big.
彼得见到我后  一副做了亏心事的样子
When Peter saw me, he looked guilty as hell.
于是我就走开了
So I just kept walking.
你没有问他吗
And you didn't ask him about it?
我后来问了
Yeah, I did later,
但他说没事  我就没管
but he said it was nothing, so I just let it go.
你在楼梯间里看到了小混混
You saw a gangbanger in your stairwell,
结果什么都不管
and you just let it go?
这是一个高压环境  探长
This is a high-stress environment, detective.
我们不问那么多
We don't ask a lot of questions
不打听员工做了什么  来撑过每一天
about what our people do to -- to get through the day.
好吧  你能跟画像师描述一下那个人吗
Okay. Do you think you can describe him to a sketch artist?
可以的
I think so.
好的  我需要彼得所有同事的名字
Great. I need the names of all of Peter's associates here at work.
当然
Of course.
蕾妮有新发现
Lanie's got something for us.
仍然没有自卫伤的迹象
Still no indication of defensive wounds,
但我在查他指甲里的DNA时发现了这个
but I did find this when I checked his nails for DNA.
数字
Numbers.
7  2  3  5  9  8
"7, 2, 3, 5, 9, 8."
他在四五天前用钢笔写的
He wrote it in pen I'd say four or five days ago.
但我不是为了这个才叫你们过来
But that's not why I called you.
看这个
Look at this.
在他胸口  Y型缝线的旁边
On his chest, next to the "Y" incision.
-看什么  -很微小
- Look at what? - It's subtle --
小得我差点都忽略了
so subtle, I almost missed it.
我觉得这是他衬衫被扯开的原因
But I think it explains why his shirt was ripped open.
-看到这里颗粒状的皮肤吗  -嗯
- You see this grainy material? - Yeah.
这是胶水残留
It's adhesive residue.
事实上  残留痕迹
In fact, there's a residue pattern
从肚子一直到胸口
from his belly to his chest.
胶水
Adhesive?
从这个痕迹看
Looking at the pattern,
我觉得这只华尔街之狼戴着窃听器
I'd say your wall street wolf was wearing a wire.
窃听器
A wire?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
我们觉得凶手射杀他之后
We believe our killer removed it
把窃听器从死者身上拿走了
from the victim's body after shooting him.
知道他是替谁戴着窃听器吗
Do we know who he was wearing a wire for?
我们还在
Well, we're checking
跟其他执法部门核对
with other branches of law enforcement right now.
这个在凶案后报警的女人呢
What about this woman who called in the murder?
你们查到她的身份了吗
Have you been able to identify her?
科尔德罗认识的人当中
You know, no one in Cordero's life
没有人知道她是谁
seems to know who she is,
我们也不知道该去哪找她
and we have no idea where to find her.
我觉得...她来找我们了
I...think she just found us.
天呐
Oh, lord.
我得说你们的案子变得更复杂了
I'd say your case just got a lot more complicated.
怎么说  长官
What is it, sir?
她们来自联邦检察官办公室
They're from the U.S. Attorney's office.
你认识她们
You know them?
不认识照片里的女人
Uh, not the woman from the photo,
但她旁边的那个叫伊丽莎白·韦斯顿
but the woman with her is Elizabeth Weston,
是南方地区的联邦检察官
The U.S. Attorney for the southern district.
还是我妹妹
She also happens to be my sister.
维克多利亚  好久不见
Victoria. Been a while.
的确
Yes, it has.
这位是
And who is this?
我是史黛芬妮·葛马科  联邦助理检察官
I'm Stefanie Goldmark, assistant U.S. Attorney.
我们为了科尔德罗被杀一案而来
We're here about the Cordero murder.
那就有趣了
Oh, well, that's funny,
因为我们对此也有许多疑问
because we have a few questions about that ourselves.
首先  葛马科女士
Starting, Ms. Goldmark,
你用公共电话报警时
with why you didn't identify yourself
为什么不肯透露自己的身份
when you made that 911 call from the pay phone.
因为我让她别透露的
Because I instructed her not to.
我不能暴露我们的调查
I couldn't afford to compromise our investigation.
什么调查
What investigation?
我们能找个地方私下谈吗
Is there somewhere private we can talk?
伊丽莎白  到底是什么事
All right, Elizabeth, what's this all about?
死者是我们的秘密线人
Your victim was a confidential informant for my office
我们在对哈丁集团进行刑事调查
in an ongoing criminal investigation of JP Harding.
所以科尔德罗戴着窃听器
Which is why Cordero was wearing a wire.
对  因为哈丁集团在65楼
Yes, and since JP Harding is on the 65th floor,
所以我们无法实时监控
we couldn't monitor it live.
科尔德罗每天早上戴上  晚上上交
Cordero put it on every morning and turned it in every night,
连同相应的录音设备
along with the attached recording device.
但昨晚他没有上交
Only last night, he didn't.
我去他的公寓查看情况
I went to his apartment to see what happened.
于是发现他死了  窃听器也不在了
That's when I found him, and the wire was gone.
我们认为窃听器录下了
We think that there was something key
对我们调查很关键的信息
to our investigation on that wire
而他也因此被杀
and that's why he was killed.
你们掌握了什么线索
So where are you on leads?
弹道科在查子弹的来历
Well, uh, ballistics is running the slug,
但目前的线索只有这个画像
but right now the only lead is this sketch,
由科尔德罗先生的老板杰米·波曼提供
provided by Mr. Cordero's boss, Jamie Berman.
他看到过这个人和被害人一起
It's of a man he saw with our victim.
还是别太相信这个画像
Well, I wouldn't put much credence in that sketch.
为什么
Why? Why is that?
因为波曼是我们这次调查的目标
Because Berman is the target of our investigation.
杰米·波曼  哈丁集团的负责人
Jamie Berman, head of JP Harding?
我们试图立案起诉他很多年了
We've been trying to mount a case against him for years --
内线交易  证券欺诈
Insider trading, securities fraud.
我们知道他做了
We know he's doing it.
但一直没拿到证据
We just haven't been able to get proof.
除非能够打入内部
Not without getting inside.
波曼很谨慎
Berman's too careful.
上个月我们有了突破口
Then, last month, we caught a break.
彼得·科尔德罗在一次盘查中
Peter Cordero was found with a baggie of cocaine
被搜出一袋可卡因
during a stop-and-frisk.
由于他还是青少年时就持有过毒品
With his priors for possession when he was a teen,
他面临着5到10年的监禁
he was facing 5 to 10.
你们让科尔德罗和你们合作
You got Cordero to play ball.
他欣然同意了豁免协议
He jumped at an immunity deal.
他已经掌握了一些有价值的信息
He'd already gotten valuable information
存在窃听录音器里
on his wire recordings.
但是昨天  他本来应该
But yesterday, he was scheduled
和波曼单独面谈
to meet with Berman one-on-one.
逼他说出他干的一些勾当
He was gonna push him to open up about some of his deals.
科尔德罗可能逼太紧了
Cordero may have pushed too hard.
我们认为波曼在会面时识破了科尔德罗
We think Berman made Cordero in that meeting.
所以你们认为杰米·波曼
So you think Jamie Berman's somehow responsible
与科尔德罗的死有关
for Cordero's death?
是的  如果波曼知道
Well, if Berman knew
自己在录音带上供认了罪行
he had incriminated himself on tape...
他会不惜一切把它夺回来的
He'd go to any lengths to get it back.
维多利亚  调查还在继续
Victoria, this investigation is ongoing,
如果将消息透露给波曼或哈丁集团的人
and exposing it to Mr. Berman or anyone at JP Harding
就会违反联邦法律
would break federal statutes.
但我觉得你和你的团队
But I thought that this was something
必须知道这些事
that you and your team needed to know.
那是当然
I'd certainly say so.
那么如果案件的调查出现了重大进展
So I trust that you will keep my office in the loop
你们一定会通知我们
if there are any... significant developments.
清楚了吗
Is that clear?
当然
Of course.
长官  我不知道你还有个妹妹
Sir, I didn't -- I didn't know you had a sister.
现在你知道了
Oh, well, now you do.
南部地区的联邦检察官
U.S. Attorney for the southern district?
这可不是什么小事
That's a really big deal.
为什么盖茨以前从没有提过她
Why hasn't Gates ever mentioned her before?
不知道  但她们之间
I don't know, but there was definitely a subtle chill
绝对有点僵
between the two of them.
有点僵
"A subtle chill"?
我看是极地漩涡
More like a polar vortex.
我猜她们俩过去应该发生了点什么
I'm guessing something happened between them in the past --
十分私人的事
Something deeply personal
盖茨不愿我们知道
that Gates does not want us to know about.
如果你去问她我就给你一美金
I'll give you a dollar if you ask her.
-才不  -别这样  你不好奇吗
- No way. - Come on. Aren't you curious?
好奇啊  但我太喜欢我的工作了
Yeah, but I like my job too much.
联邦检察官的说法可能有点靠谱
Hey, so, uh, there may be something to the U.S. Attorney's theory.
我查了一下科尔德罗的日历
I checked Cordero's calendar.
他昨天下午五点的确安排了
He was scheduled to meet with Berman
和波曼会面
at 5 p.m. yesterday.
不管他们说了什么  情况有点不妙
And whatever they talked about, it got heated.
你怎么知道的
How do you know that?
根据楼层的监控录像
According to building security,
两人很快就离开了
the two of them left shortly after
并且看起来像起了争执
and seemed to be in the middle of a fight.
是的  彼得和我昨天说过话
Yeah, Peter and I had words yesterday.
怎么了
So what?
今天早上我们谈话的时候
So, you didn't tell us about that
-你没告诉我们  -因为这不相关
- when we talked this morning. - 'Cause it wasn't relevant.
怎么不相关呢
How is it not relevant?
录像显示你们俩同时离开
The video shows you leaving together.
两小时后  他就死了
Two hours later, he's dead.
不相关是因为我没有杀他
It's not relevant because I didn't kill him.
说真的  探长  我有什么动机呢
Honestly, detective, what would be my motive?
你们俩到底为什么起了争执
What exactly were the two of you arguing about?
一笔生意
A business deal.
为一笔生意的话  你太激动了吧
You looked pretty worked up for a business deal.
这笔生意很重要
There was a lot riding on it.
什么生意
What was the deal?
客户隐私  探长
Client confidentiality, detective.
我不能说
I'm not at liberty to discuss it.
你和彼得在此之前会过面
You had a meeting with Peter before that.
你们那时候在谈什么
What were you speaking about then?
其他的财务问题
Other financial matters.
什么样的财务问题
What kind of financial matters?
敏感的问题  任何对此的探讨
Sensitive ones, any discussion of which,
即使是跟执法部门
even with law enforcement,
都可能被认为是内线交易
would be considered insider trading.
除非你们有法院的传票
So unless you have a subpoena --
还有谁参加了会面
Who else was at the meeting?
只有我们俩
Just the two of us.
你离开大厅之后去了哪里
And what did you do after you left the lobby?
我们沿着拉菲尔街往上走到喷泉就分开了
Oh, we walked up Lafayette and parted ways around spring.
那时候几点
What time was that?
6点15左右
Around 6:15.
你八点到十点间去了哪里
Where were you between 8:00 and 10:00?
坐在马戏团餐厅我平时的座位上
At my usual table at le cirque.
你们可以去查
Feel free to check.
时间到了
It's time.
抱歉
Now, if you'll excuse me,
我和美联储有个电话会议
I have a conference call with the Fed.
对了  如果你还想找我  探长
Oh, and if you want to talk to me again, detective,
给我的律师打电话
call my lawyer.
马戏团餐厅确认波曼
Le cirque confirms that Berman was there
8点到10点25都在那儿
8:00 p.m. till 10:25.
不可能是他
Couldn't have been him.
因为像波曼那样的人不会自己动手
'Cause a guy like berman isn't gonna get his hands dirty.
他肯定雇了别人
He's gonna hire someone.
你妹妹是对的  波曼是幕后黑手
No, your sister's right. Berman is behind this.
说到你妹妹
And speaking of your sister --
打住
Let's not.
如果波曼是幕后黑手
If Berman is behind this,
他会用尽一切手段来保护自己
he will do everything he can to protect himself.
知道联邦政府的人在监视他
Knowing that the Feds are watching him,
他肯定会小心翼翼地隐藏自己
he would be careful to cover his tracks.
要查到他身上简直不可能
It's gonna be next to impossible to trace this back to him.
那我们现在能确定的就是
So, all we're really sure of
他给我们的这个画像
is that the sketch he gave us
是个虚构的陷阱
is a load of fictitious crap
用来误导我们的调查方向
meant to send us in the wrong direction.
素描不是虚构的
It's not as fictitious as you think.
我刚拿到杀科尔德罗那把枪的弹道报告
I just got the ballistics back on the bullet that killed Cordero.
弹痕和三个月前布朗克斯区一家酒馆的
Striations match a slug that was pulled from a robbery shooting
抢劫枪击案的子弹相符
at a bodega in the Bronx three months ago.
警方的证据不足以立案
The detectives couldn't make a case,
但三个最可能的疑犯都是帮派成员
but their three best suspects were gang members,
包括这个人
including this guy.
-同一个人  -同一把枪
- Same guy. - Same gun.
海克托·努涅斯
Hector Nunez?
对  掌控着卡瓦列罗斯帮派的布朗克斯南部地区
Yeah, runs the south Bronx territory of los Caballeros gang.
前科包括暴力袭击  杀人未遂
Priors include assault, attempted manslaughter,
以及合谋分销可卡因
and conspiracy to distribute cocaine.
不  你搞错了
No, you're wrong.
彼得从不沾染可卡因  他厌恶毒品
Peter had nothing to do with cocaine. He hated drugs.
你知道上个月他因为持有毒品被捕吗
Do you know he was arrested last month for possession?
不可能  我了解彼得
That's impossible. I know Peter.
他不可能吸毒的
He'd never use that stuff.
玛利亚  你确定吗
Are you sure, Maria?
上星期有人看到这个男人给了他一个包裹
Because he was seen receiving a package last week from this guy.
不  不  这不可能
No. No. It -- it can't be.
你认得他吗
Do you recognize him?
他是海克托·努涅斯
Hector Nunez.
是彼得从小玩到大的好朋友
He was Peter's best friend growing up.
但他后来进了帮派
But then he got mixed up in a gang,
也想把彼得拉进去
And he tried to drag Peter in, too.
后来海克托就变了  变得危险
Afterwards, Hector changed. He became dangerous.
彼得在十多年前就和他撇清关系了
Peter cut ties with him over a decade ago.
你知道为什么他和彼得又牵扯上了吗
Can you think of any reason why he'd be back in Peter's life?
海克托是个恶魔
Hector was a devil.
彼得根本不会再和他牵扯不清的
Peter would have never gotten mixed up with him again...
除非是万不得已
...unless he didn't have a choice.
这里和华尔街真是相去甚远呐
This is a long way from Wall Street.
这说不通啊  如果彼得真吸毒了
This doesn't make any sense. If Peter was into drugs,
他肯定有钱从市区买毒品
he had enough money to get them from downtown.
明知道海克托很危险
Why would he risk getting them
为什么还从他那儿买毒品呢
from someone that he knew was dangerous?
就是这儿  热舞乐部
There it is -- el baile club.
卡瓦列罗斯帮派的非官方集聚地
Yeah, unofficial headquarters of los Caballeros.
跟紧我
Stick close.
如果海克托真像传言的那么危险
If Hector's as dangerous as advertised,
可能会有些麻烦
things might get a little hairy.
麻烦[多毛]是我的专长
Hairy's my middle name.
这话讲出来不如心里想的那么好
That sounded a lot better in my head.
你确定我们没走错吧
Are you sure this is the right place?
那些人看起来不像危险人物
Those guys don't look very dangerous.
那些人呢
What about those guys?
那些荷枪实弹的啊
Ah, you mean the heavily-armed ones.
我们要找海克托·努涅斯
We're looking for Hector Nunez.
海克托·努涅斯
Hector Nunez?
我是贝克特探长  纽约警局
Detective Beckett, NYPD.
探长  你不该来这儿的  受伤就不好了
Detective, you shouldn't be here. You could get hurt.
这附近不大安全
It's a dangerous neighborhood.
也许我该把你带到我的地盘问话
Yeah, well, maybe I should take you down to my neighborhood.
给你省点时间吧
Let me save you some time.
不管你想问什么  我都没做过
Whatever it is, I didn't do it.
那你也没听过一个叫彼得·科尔德罗的人了
And I suppose you've never heard of a Peter Cordero, either.
彼得怎么了
What about Peter?
他死了
He's dead.
谁干的
Who did this?
我们以为是你...
Well, we were thinking you...
...你也许你能告诉我们
...might...be able to... tell us.
我绝不会伤害彼得
I'd never hurt peter.
他曾是我最好的朋友
He was my best friend.
我们小时候  帮派想招募他
When we were kids and the gang wanted to take him,
我阻止了
I wouldn't let them.
我知道他能拥有更好的生活
I knew he could do better.
那他怎么会被你的枪射杀呢
So how did he end up shot and killed with your gun?
他出了什么事
Something was going on with him.
上周他时隔多年头一次打电话找我
He called me last week -- first time in years.
说他在做什么能赚钱的买卖
Said he was into some deal that was gonna make him rich,
但很危险
but it was dangerous.
他需要保护自己  以防出事
In case something went wrong, he needed to protect himself.
他说要一把武器
He said he need a weapon.
你是说你把那把枪给了他
You're saying you gave him that gun?
对  他说他一直被监视
Well, he said he couldn't buy one himself
不能自己去买枪
'cause he was being watched all the time.
你在楼梯间给他的包裹里就是枪吗
Was that what was in the package you gave him in the stairwell?
嗯
Yeah.
他所说的买卖是毒品吗
That deal that he was into -- was it drugs?
不是毒品  是钱  和银行账户有关
Not drugs, money. Something to do with bank accounts.
银行账户
"Bank accounts"?
上周四夜里  他来找我
Last Thursday night, he came to me,
要我最后再帮他个忙
said he needed one last favor.
让我把一个信封交给市中心什么银行的经理
He wanted me to take an envelope to a manager at some bank in midtown
好像是瑞士联邦银行什么的
Suisse Federal or something.
他为什么不自己去呢  为什么让你去
Why couldn't he just do it himself? Why would he need you?
他说不能被人看到他去银行  风险太大
Said he couldn't afford to be seen at the bank -- was too risky.
信封里是什么
What was in the envelope?
他说是过户指令什么的
He said something about transfer instructions.
信封封起来了  但有个银行账号
It was sealed, but there was a bank account number
写在信封外面
written on the outside.
你记得账号吗
Do you remember the number?
为防出事我写下来了
Wrote it down in case something went wrong.
还真出事了
I guess it did.
不是他右手上写的六位数字
Not the same six-digit number that was on his hand.
我把信封送去银行之后
After I took the envelope to the bank,
我打电话给彼得告诉他送到了
I called Peter at work to confirm it was done.
那是我们最后一次通话
That's the last time we talked.
海克托的不在场证明确认了
Hector's alibi checks out.
彼得被杀时
He was at lady of mercy
他在仁慈圣母养老院看望他母亲
nursing home visiting his mom when Peter was killed.
神秘的财务交易
Mysterious financial transactions,
需要用到枪的危险买卖
a deal so dangerous he needed a gun...
我觉得你妹妹的重要证人
Seem to me there's a lot more
有很多事没有告诉她
to your sister's star witness than she knew.
没告诉她还是她故意没告诉我们
"Than she knew" or than she chose to tell us about?
长官
Sir?
问过瑞士联邦银行的经理了
Yo. Talked to the manager at Suisse Federal.
他证实确实有那个账号
He confirmed that a bank account with those numbers exists,
但他拒绝透露任何信息
But he refused to give out any information on it.
那他有没有说这是彼得·科尔德罗的账户
Did he at least acknowledge it was Peter Cordero's account?
他没说  因为他自己也不知道
He couldn't, because he didn't know himself.
这是一个私密数字账户
It's a numbered account set up for privacy,
要访问它必须要有密码才行
so the only way that anyone can access it is with a password.
那我们岂不是没办法知道科尔德罗在干嘛了
So there's no way to know what Cordero was doing.
没办法
No.
除非
Unless...
六位数
Six digits?
这看起来挺像个密码的
Seems kind of password-y to me.
好了  念给我听
Okay, read it to me.
723598.
快出来吧
Come on.
进去了
We're in.
卡塞尔  你又成功了
Castle, you've done it again.
里面有多少钱
What's it say?
余额是零
The balance is zero dollars.
零  这个看上去人畜无害
Zero dollars? That doesn't seem very dangerous.
感觉就像是寻宝探险的最后
Feels like the end of a treasure hunt
你打开宝箱结果里面装满了沙子
where you open up the chest and it's just full of sand.
等等  查一下努涅斯先生说他转账的那天
Wait. Go to the day Mr. Nunez claims he did the transfer,
三月二十一日
March 21st.
我的天  2500万美元
Oh, my god. $25 million.
这宝箱里装的是金沙啊
Whoa. That's some expensive sand.
看来这笔钱是在
Looks like it came into the account
前一天早上8:34转入的
the day before at 8:34 in the morning,
随后海克托就把这笔钱转走了
and then Hector transferred it out.
神秘的2500万美元转账把他害死了
A secret $25 million transfer that got him killed.
科尔德罗到底卷入什么麻烦事了
What the hell was Cordero into?
好的
Right.
有什么好消息吗
Any luck?
没  我刚和瑞士联邦银行的领导通话
No. I just talked to the head of Suisse Federal Bank.
根据国际银行管理规则
Given international banking regulations,
我们没办法知道
there's no way to tell
这笔钱是哪里来的或者汇到哪里去了
where that money came from or were it went.
这笔钱是不是科尔德罗的都无法确定
Or if the money's even Cordero's.
他也许是在帮别人转移
He could have been moving it for someone else.
长官  如果这笔转账是和科尔德罗的死有关
Sir, if this transaction was somehow responsible
而我们又无法查清它的来龙去脉
for Cordero's death and we can't track it,
那我们就可能永远也找不到凶手了
then we may never be able to find his killer.
也许还另有办法
There may be another way.
2500万美元
$25 million?
没错
That's right.
你的线人为了保密可费了不少周折
And your informant went to a great deal of trouble to keep it secret.
那你也不知道那些钱是哪里来的
And you have no idea where the money came from?
不  不过那些钱很可能是他被杀的原因
No, but odds are it's what got him killed.
伊丽莎白  如果你知道任何和这有关的
Elizabeth, if you know anything about this...
我当然什么都不知道了
Of course I don't know anything about this.
你不相信我
You don't believe me.
怪我咯
Do you blame me?
我不知道
I didn't know.
你看他费了那么大劲隐藏这笔转账
And given the lengths he went to hide the transaction,
显示是不想让我知道
he clearly didn't want me to know.
好吧
Okay, fine.
我需要查看彼得·科尔德罗的录音记录
Then I'm gonna need access to Peter Cordero's wire recordings.
为什么
For what?
因为那些录音记录里
Because there may be something on those tapes
可能有和他被害有关的内容
that's relevant to his murder.
我们都查过了
We went through them.
如果有什么的话  我们会注意到的
If there was anything on there, we would have heard it.
不仔细是听不到的
Not if you weren't listening for it.
非常抱歉  维多利亚  那些录音记录
I'm sorry, Victoria, but those wire recordings
是一项机密调查的一部分
are a privileged part of a confidential investigation.
我不能给你查看
I can't give you access.
是不能还是不愿
"Can't" Or "Won't"?
你觉得我是瞎了吗
Do you think I'm blind?
抓住像波曼这样厉害的人物
Bringing down someone as big as Berman,
你就能呼风唤雨了
you'd be able to write your own ticket.
市长  司法部长
The mayor's office, Attorney General --
你所梦想的一切一切
Everything you always dreamed of.
可你需要科尔德罗的证词
But you need Cordero's testimony,
假如他在作证的时候参与了什么非法活动
and if he was involved in anything dirty while acting as a witness,
就会毁了你整个案子
It'd jeopardize your whole case.
那就是为什么你不愿意给我那些录音
That's why you won't give us those tapes --
因为你害怕我们会找到不利的东西
Because you're afraid of what we might find.
抓住像波曼那样的骗子可以震慑
Taking down a shark like Berman would send a signal
所有金融圈里的骗子们
to every fraudulent actor in the financial market.
我必须顾全大局
I have to think about the greater good.
这就是你对自己说的
Oh, is that what you tell yourself
好睡个好觉吗
so you can sleep at night?
你根本不懂这里的游戏规则  不是吗
You could never play the game, could you?
所以你只好整天困在办公室里
It's why you're stuck behind a desk
而不是统领整个纽约警局
instead of running the entire force down at 1 P.P.
我才没有困在这里
I am not stuck anywhere.
我永远也不会为我维护法律
And I will never, never apologize
尽心尽力的行为而道歉
for doing my job to the letter of the law.
好了  快把那些录音资料给我
Now, I'm gonna need those wire recordings.
难道你要我向你的上级报告吗
Or do I have to go over your head?
任何你找到有关的  你先跟我说
Anything that you find, you bring it to me first.
你明白了吗
Do you understand?
我不能让你又毁了
I will not have you screw up
我另一个案子
another one of my investigations.
我们可不能邀请她
Let's not put her on the list.
是啊
Yeah.
彼得·科尔德罗
录音记录
我真为盖茨感到难过
I feel bad for Gates.
我的姐妹们根本无法共处一室
My sisters could never work together.
我跟你说  她们打起来的时候  简直
I tell you, when the two of them went at it -- whoo!
我不介意和盖茨的妹妹出去约会
I wouldn't mind going out with Gates' sister.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
要是盖茨成了你的大姨你感觉如何
How'd you like having Gates as your sister-in-law?
怎么了
What?
我想我是发现了点东西
I think I got something.
在3月21日  彼得·科尔德罗的监听器
So, on March 21st, Peter Cordero's wire
录下了海克托·努涅斯打来的电话
picked up a phone call from Hector Nunez
就是确认转账完成的那通
to confirm that the transfer was done.
电话是上午9:25打进来的
The call came in at 9:25 A.M.
这和海克托说的一致
That's pretty much what Hector said.
是的  仔细听下面两通彼得打的电话
Yeah, but listen to the next two calls that Peter makes.
他是说"我以阿曼多·加西亚的名义打电话
He's saying, "I'm calling on behalf of Armando Garcia.
"我想确认下他的钱已经收到了
"I want to make sure that his money was received.
你能确认下数量吗"
Can you confirm the amount?"
然后他说"谢谢"  随后挂断电话
Then he says, "Thank you," And then hangs up.
阿曼多·加西亚是什么人
Who's Armando Garcia?
我向哈丁集团查过了
I checked with JP Harding,
他们没有客户是叫这个名字的
but they don't have any clients by that name.
那就不是公司的生意伙伴了
So it wasn't company business?
不是  仔细听第二通电话
No. Now listen to the second call.
他到了吗  我是彼得·科尔德罗
Is he in? It's Peter Cordero calling.
所以的事情都办妥了
Hey, everything's taken care of,
不过我们时间所剩不多了
but we're running out of time.
我们得在之后几天把这事搞定
We need to get this done in the next couple days.
有问题吗
Is that gonna be a problem?
很好
Good.
一切都处理好了
"Everything's taken care of" --
说的一定是那两千五百万
That must be about the $25 million.
但之后几天到底要干什么
But what exactly was getting done in the next couple of days?
为什么会导致他被杀
And how did it get him killed?
我们得找到阿曼多·加西亚
We need to find Armando Garcia.
是  但不幸的是  这名字很常见
Yeah. Unfortunately, it's a pretty common name.
光是在美国就由几百个阿曼多·加西亚
There are hundreds of Armando Garcias in the U.S. Alone.
很难缩小范围
It's gonna be hard to narrow it down.
除非我们能查出他打给了谁
Unless we can find out who he was calling.
9点25分时  彼得应该在工作
At 9:25, Peter would have been at work.
他应该是用办公桌上的电话打的
He would've made those phone calls from his desk phone.
如果我们能拿到通话记录
If we can get those phone records,
说不定就能知道他被卷入了什么事
they could tell us what he was involved in.
我去申请搜查令
I'll put in for a warrant.
希望上午前就能拿到
Hopefully, we'll get it by morning.
想到盖茨的妹妹
You know, I was thinking about Gates' sister,
我就很好奇
and it got me wondering --
你还有没有什么我不知道的家人
do you have any family I don't know about?
我想没有
I don't think so.
那就好  因为我们这个"私密的婚礼"
Good. Because this "intimate wedding" of ours...
不是吧  你也有那么多
Oh, no. You too?
-你那边有多糟  -我有一百多个亲友
- How bad is yours? - I've got over 100.
我比你还多三百个
I'm at 300 over that.
四百个
400?!
公平点来说  毕竟我名震全球...
Well, to be fair, I am world-famous...
...吧
...ish.
听着  这只是初稿
Uh, look, it's a first draft.
再精简一下就行了
It just needs some editing.
残暴无情地精简
Brutal, ruthless editing.
卡塞尔  迈克尔·康纳利
Castle, Michael Connelly?
你都一年多没见过他了
You haven't seen him in over a year.
你不记得他怎么写你上一本书的了吗
Do you not remember what he wrote about your last book?
不行  第一个要精简的就是他
No. I think we got our first edit.
我必须得邀请康纳利
Uh, well, I have to invite Connelly,
因为万一他发现
because if he finds out
乔纳森·凯勒曼被邀请了...
that Jonathan Kellerman made the cut --
而我必须得邀请凯勒曼
And I have to invite Kellerman
是因为我得邀请韦斯·克雷文和史蒂芬·金
because I have to invite Wes Craven and Stephen King.
那我们总得找个地方下手吧
Yeah, but we got to start somewhere.
我知道从哪下手了
Well, I think I know where.
特雷莎姑姑
Aunt Theresa?
真的假的
Really?
她在脸谱网上那么说我
After what she posted about me on facebook?
她后来删了
She took it down.
好吧
Fine.
怎么办
What are we gonna do?
我们不能请五百个人来参加婚礼
We can't have 500 people at the wedding.
你们好  两位
Hello, you two.
中立的第三方来帮我们了
Ah, help has arrived in the form of a neutral third party.
一个生来就残暴无情的人
Someone who was born to be brutal and ruthless.
多谢夸奖  多谢
Thank you. Thank you.
你们还在研究邀请名单啊
Oh, still working on the invite list, I see.
是啊  你能跟我们一起来吗
Yes, actually. And would you mind joining us?
乐意之至
Love to.
我去拿我的名单
Let me get my list.
我把所有名字都写下来之后
Oh, you know, I had no idea how many people I needed to invite
才知道我要请多少人
until I wrote them all down.
好消息
Good news.
我把我妈的名单和我的交叉比对了
I crossed-referenced my mother's list with my list.
有三个人是重合的哦
We have three names in common.
三个  真是太好了
Wow, three names. That's...great.
所以人数从585降到582了吗
That takes us from, what, 585 to 582?
一定有更好的精简办法
There's got to be a better way to cut this down.
瑞恩  你的婚礼规模就挺小
Ryan, you guys kept your wedding small.
大概就一百人吧
What was it -- like 100 people?
对  我们只花得起这个钱
Yeah, that's all we could afford.
你是怎么精简名单的
How did you contain the list?
有很多亲戚都记恨上我了
I have a lot of relatives who hate me now.
科尔德罗电话的搜查令下来了
So, the warrant on Cordero's phone finally came through.
不管这个阿曼多·加西亚是谁
Whoever this Armando Garcia is,
一定跟委内瑞拉有关
it has something to do with Venezuela.
彼得就是从那来的
That's where Peter was from.
第一个确认那两千五百万的电话
Yeah, that first call confirming the $25 million?
是打给一家委内瑞拉银行的
It was made to a bank in Venezuela.
第二个电话是打给委内瑞拉领事馆的
The second call was to the Venezuela Consulate
就在市里
right here in the city.
是那里一个高级官员的直拨电话
It was the direct line of a senior official there --
叫路易·德加多
a Luis Delgado.
秘密电汇
Clandestine wire transfers,
高级领事馆官员
a high-ranking consulate official,
都和这个神秘的阿曼多·加西亚有关
all circling around the mysterious Armando Garcia.
科尔德罗到底在干什么
What was Cordero doing?
我不知道  不过迫不及待想去查出真相了
I don't know, but I can't wait to find out.
瑞士银行户口  秘密汇款
Swiss bank accounts, secret money transfers --
全都笼罩着一种国际化阴谋的气息
It's got international intrigue written all over it.
就是简单的护照申请
It was just a simple passport request.
护照申请
A passport request?
对  他就是为了这事打来的
Yes, that's why he called.
那钱呢
Well, what about the money?
恐怕我不知道什么钱的事
I'm afraid I don't know anything about any money.
真的吗
Really?
那我想你也从没听说过阿曼多·加西亚吧
I suppose you've never heard of Armando Garcia, either?
阿曼多·加西亚
Armando Garcia?
不  我当然听说过阿曼多·加西亚
Yes, of course I heard of Armando Garcia.
你听说过
You have?
护照就是给他办的
That's who I got the passport for.
等等  我以为是给彼得·科尔德罗办的
Wait, I thought that the passport was for Peter Cordero.
是啊  彼得·科尔德罗  阿曼多·加西亚
Yes, Peter Cordero, Armando Garcia...
这是同一个人
...it's the same guy.
他姑姑和姑父搬来纽约的时候
When his aunt and uncle moved into New York,
他为了融入环境改名了
he changed his name to fit in.
他的本名叫阿曼多·加西亚
But his birth name was Armando Garcia.
他是在给自己汇钱
He was sending the money to himself.
你说他要申请护照
You said he was requesting a passport.
委内瑞拉护照吗
A Venezuelan passport?
当然
Yes, of course.
科尔德罗要重新申请委内瑞拉国籍
Cordero applied to re-establish his venezuelan citizenship,
我们很乐意帮忙
and we were more than happy to oblige.
以阿曼多·加西亚的名义
Under the name "Armando Garcia"?
没错  不过
That's right. But, uh...
他的申请上有一点很奇怪
there was something odd about his request.
他想在墨西哥城拿护照
He asked to pick up the passport in Mexico City.
墨西哥城  他说了为什么吗
Mexico City? Did he say why?
没有  不过他昨天就该去那边的大使馆拿的
No, but he was supposed to get it yesterday at our embassy there.
他订了机票
He had booked a flight
从墨西哥城飞加拉加斯[委内瑞拉首都]
from Mexico City to Caracas that night.
他想跑
He was running away?
不只是跑
Not just running away,
还有彻底改变他的身份
changing his identity completely.
他从未打算来作证
He never intended to testify.
他只是在欺骗我妹妹
He was just stringing my sister along
直到他能逃走
until he could escape.
他只需要开车去墨西哥
All he had to do was drive to Mexico.
一旦他登上去加拉加斯[委内瑞拉首都]的飞机
Once he boarded that flight to Caracas
在他用新的信用卡买的新的身份之下生活
under his new identity, paid for with a new credit card,
彼得·科尔德罗就会从此消失了
Peter Cordero would cease to exist.
你妹妹永远都找不到他
Your sister would never find him.
但他并不想空手离去
But he wasn't gonna leave empty-handed,
所以他铤而走险地做了最后一笔交易
so he made one last desperate deal.
他被杀的那晚
The night he was killed,
他准备着带着两千五百万
he was preparing to disappear forever
就此消失
along with the $25 million.
不可能就这么凭空变出来两千五百万
You don't just conjure $25 million out of thin air.
肯定是有来源的
It came from somewhere.
而且鉴于这种情况  肯定还是非法的
And, given the circumstances, nowhere legal.
如果你是对的  这会毁掉我妹妹的案子
If you're right, it'll destroy my sister's case.
他做的所有证词会被作废
All his testimony will be tainted.
长官  你想让我们怎么做
Sir, what do you want us to do?
查明真相
Find the truth.
要想查明真相  我们需要知道
In order to do that, we need to know
这笔钱的来源  但是这根本没办法查出
where the money came from, and there's no way to find out.
或许还是可以查出的
Uh, maybe there is.
阿曼多·加西亚的那个秘密的信用卡
You know that secret Armando Garcia credit card?
他用来买机票的那张
You know, the one he used to buy the plane ticket?
我们在那上面找到了另外一笔交易
We found another charge on it
他在一处网吧里租了一台电脑
for a computer station he rented at an internet cafe.
他在那里的时间点
He was there the exact same time
和两千五百万在他账户出现的时间点相吻合
that $25 million showed up in his account.
不管他在那做了什么  都跟转账脱不了干系
So whatever he was doing there was related to the transfer.
网吧里有监控录像
That cafe has security video.
如果我们能看到电脑屏幕
If we can get a look at the computer screen
或者是彼得在键盘上打了什么
or Peter's fingers on the keyboard,
或许我们能弄清楚那笔钱的来源
Maybe we can figure out where that money came from.
和他的死因
And why he was killed.
你还好吗
Sir, uh...you okay?
只是在想如何在她不怪我的前提下
Oh, just trying to figure out how to tell my sister
告诉我妹妹她的案子完蛋了
her case is compromised without her blaming me.
你只是在做好你的本职工作  她为什么要怪你呢
Why would she blame you when you're just doing you job?
我们之间有段往事
There's a history.
1998年
1998.
我刚刚成为内部事务处的主管
I had just been made head of internal affairs.
伊丽莎白在地方检察官办公室里任职
Elizabeth was in the D.A.'s office.
我们自称"无敌姐妹花"
We called ourselves "The Dynamic Duo."
在那时候  伊丽莎白快要
At the time, Elizabeth was closing in
扳倒一个在东纽约的海洛因走私团体
on a heroin ring in east New York,
他们安插了卧底
And they had an undercover inside.
他的证词是案件的关键
His testimony was key to the case, but...
他并不清白
He was dirty?
他在伊丽莎白立案的几次查缴中
He skimmed a few eight balls off the very bust
中饱私囊
Elizabeth was building her case around.
当我们处抓到他倒卖时
And when my office caught him re-selling it,
她来找我  求我不要控诉
She came to me, begged me not to file charges,
让我顾全大局
asked me to think of the greater good.
我那天也尽职了
I did my job that day, too.
从此之后我们的关系再也没回到从前
Hasn't been the same between us since.
监控录像传过来的
Security video is in.
科尔德罗在那里
There's Cordero.
但是角度正好在监控器对面
But the angle is over the monitor.
我们看不见电脑屏幕
We can't see the screen.
或者是键盘
Or the keyboard.
这根本不可能看出来他在干什么
There's no way to tell what he's doing.
等一下  等等  他是谁
Wait a minute. Wait. Who is that?
看看时间代码
Take a look at the time code.
跟两千五百万出现在
It's right around the moment
科尔德罗瑞士银行账户上的时间点相差无几
the $25 million got into Cordero's swiss bank account.
就是他  是他把钱转给科尔德罗的
It's him. He transferred the money to Cordero.
从一个难以追踪的IP地址并由一个
A covert transfer from an untraceable I.P. address,
使用化名的人支付的秘密转账
paid for under an alias.
他为了掩盖身份
These people took extraordinary measures
真是无所不用其极
to keep from being discovered.
放大
Zoom in.
暂停
Freeze it.
等等  这是科尔德罗的上司杰米·波曼
Wait. That's Cordero's boss. That Jamie Berman.
为什么波曼秘密转给科尔德罗两千五百万
Why would Berman secretly pay Cordero $25 million?
只有一个原因
Only one reason.
科尔德罗一定告诉了波曼
Cordero must have told Berman
关于美国检察官的调查
about the U.S. Attorney's investigation.
波曼用钱收买他撤案
And Berman was paying him to throw the case.
如果波曼用钱收买了科尔德罗去撤案
If Berman was paying Cordero to throw the case,
那他窃听器上的录音就全是假的
then the recordings from his wire were all lies.
波曼在给美国检察官
Berman was feeding
虚假的证据
the U.S. Attorney's office false evidence.
如果伊丽莎白是以此为据来打官司的话
And if Elizabeth was building her case on that,
她会被辩护方杀的片甲不留
She would have been torn apart by the defense.
即便不能永远阻止她调查
Keeping her out of Berman's business
也至少可以让波曼消停一阵子
for quite a while, if not forever.
一直以来  我妹妹以为她要将波曼拿下了
All this time, my sister thought she was taking down Berman
事实上是他努力把她拿下
when he was really trying to take down her.
但只有一件事解释不通
The one thing it doesn't explain, though,
为什么科尔德罗被杀
is why Cordero was killed.
波曼肯定脱不了干系
Berman's up to his eyeballs in this.
你把他带进局里  查出他都知道些什么
You bring him in here and find out what he knows.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
恐怕你犯了个错误  探长
I'm afraid you're mistaken, Detective.
我没有给科尔德罗先生转过钱
I didn't transfer any money to Mr. Cordero,
更不会转了两千五百万
Certainly not $25 million.
然而你按下那个按钮的一瞬间
And yet, the moment that you press that button,
两千五百万出现在了科尔德罗的账户上
$25 million showed up in Cordero's account.
你没有任何证据证明那个账户是属于科尔德罗先生的
You have no evidence that account belongs to Mr. Cordero,
就像你没有任何证据证明是我客户汇的款
Just as you have no evidence that money came from my client.
那你为什么和他一块在网吧里
Then why were you with him in that internet cafe?
那里的咖啡不错
They have good coffee.
我认为你不怕麻烦想让转账
I think there's a reason why you went out of you way
成为一个秘密是有原因的
to keep that transfer a secret.
我认为科尔德罗告诉你他被迫
I think Cordero told you that he was being forced
成了美国检察官的线人
to be an informant for the U.S. Attorney.
他知道自己永远都不可能复职了
And knowing that he would never be able to work again,
他和你做了一笔交易
He struck a deal with you.
用两千五百万来换你提供虚假证据
$25 million in exchange for providing false evidence
从而破坏调查
to undermine the investigation.
什么调查
What investigation?
你很清楚是什么调查
You know exactly what investigation.
当你发现他完成不了他的任务
And when you found out that he wasn't gonna finish the job --
他要带着你给他的钱远走高飞
That he was gonna leave town and take your money with him --
你杀了他
You had him killed.
然后你把他戴在身上的窃听器拿走
And then you took the wire that you knew he was wearing
来掩盖你谋杀的一切记录证据
to cover up any recorded evidence of the murder.
这都是胡乱猜测
That's all wild speculation.
更何况你连事实都搞不清楚
Not to mention, you have your facts wrong.
你说彼得被杀时身上戴着窃听器
You said Peter was wearing his wire when he was killed.
恐怕那不可能
I'm afraid that's not possible.
你知道窃听器的事
So you knew about the wire?
你承认你跟他一块参与了这事
You admit you were in on it with him.
杰米
Jamie.
知道这个又不犯法
It's not illegal to know.
而且我向你保证
And I guarantee you
你永远都不可能把我和转账联系起来
you will never link me to that payment,
这样你永远都不可能证明干扰证人
So you'll never be able to prove witness tampering.
但是没错  我知道窃听器的事
But, yeah, I knew about the wire.
彼得被杀时身上没戴窃听器
And Peter wasn't wearing it when he was killed
因为他已经把窃听器放在
because he had already left it for the feds
拉斐特街和斯普林大道交界处的秘密传递点了
at the dead drop at Lafayette and Spring.
你怎么会
How do you even --
是在你们俩一块散步的时候
The walk that you took together.
你和他在一起
You were with him.
我看着他打开其中一个信箱门
I saw him go into the mailbox door
然后把窃听器放到了其中一个盒子里
and put it into one of those boxes.
谢谢你们能来
Thank you for coming.
应该的
Of course.
案件有突破了
There's been a break in the case?
是的  的确
Yes, actually.
关于彼得·科尔德罗被谋杀一案
New information has surfaced
有新的线索浮出水面了
about Peter Cordero's murder.
事实上  美国检察官办公室的某人
In fact, it seems someone in the U.S. Attorney's Office
对科尔德罗在被害当晚没有将窃听器
lied about Cordero not leaving his wire
放在传递点这件事撒了谎
at the dead drop the night of his death.
没有人撒谎
No one lied.
我亲自去情报传递点看过  窃听器不在
I went to the drop myself. It wasn't there.
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth?
你来告诉她吧
Tell her.
史黛芬妮  如果彼得没有把他的窃听器上交的话
Stefanie, if Peter never turned in his wire,
那天的录音又怎么会出现在你的电脑上呢
how did that day's recordings end up on your computer?
虽说你把那些录音删除了
See, even though you erased them,
但是我们的技术部成功地修复了
the tech department here was able to recover...
所有东西
everything.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
按照标准程序  你应该在第二天一早
Standard procedure was to turn them over
将录音上交  以供分析
for analysis the next morning.
但是你那天晚上就先听了录音
But you listened to those tapes that night,
而且你还听到了一些本不该听到的东西
and you heard something you weren't supposed to,
至少是在科尔德罗消失前不想让你听到的东西
at least not until Cordero was gone.
我怀揣着美国梦来到了美国
I came to the U.S. believing in the American dream.
于是我在这腐败的世界  给腐败贪心的人打工
So I worked hard and tried to be honest in a corrupt world,
并且还能做到艰苦奋斗  刚正不阿
working for corrupt and greedy people,
那是因为我还坚信着美国梦
because I still believed.
可是当你  美国政府
But when you, the U.S. government,
就为了找个人作证  就嫁祸我藏毒
plants drugs on me, threatens to destroy my future,
还威胁说要毁了我的未来
all because you need someone to testify,
我还怎么能继续坚信下去
how am I supposed to still believe?
我已经尽我所能地按规矩办事
I did everything I could to play by the rules,
但其他人没有这样做
but no one else does.
所以当你们听到这段录音时  我已经消失了
So by the time you hear this, I'll be gone.
我们讯问过逮到科尔德罗的那位警官
We brought in the cop that busted Cordero.
他承认是你指使他嫁祸科尔德罗藏毒的
He confessed to planting the cocaine... on your orders.
你为什么要这么做  史黛芬妮
Why, Stefanie?
你说过你需要一个内线
You said you needed someone on the inside,
才能对波曼立案  你说这是为了大局
to make the case against Berman, for the greater good.
那也不是这样做呀
No. Not like this.
当你听到录音
When you heard that recording
发现彼得要潜逃
and found out Peter was leaving,
你知道这一切都会大白于天下
you knew it would all come out.
所以你就去了他家
So you went to his place.
我是去试图说服他  但他不肯听我解释
I-I went to try and talk to him, but he wouldn't listen.
然后你看到了他的枪
And then you saw his gun,
就临时起意要永远封住他的嘴
and you made sure that his story would never get out.
接下来你还把现场布置得像是
And then you made it look like
有人为了夺走窃听录音带而将他杀害
he was killed for that recording.
贝克特警探  卡塞尔先生
Detective Beckett, Mr. Castle.
我想赞扬你们  在顶着来自我和我办公室的压力下
I would like to commend you for your exemplary work
还能如此出色地完成任务
in the face of head winds from me and my office.
谢谢夸奖
Oh, thank you.
但我们只是在警监的领导下
But, I mean, we were just all doing our jobs,
做了自己的本职工作而已
following our captain's lead.
你追踪到那两千五百万美金了吗
Did you manage to track down that $25 million?
追到了  科尔德罗先生把一大部分
Yes, it turns out that Mr. Cordero
都捐献了  用来重建他的家乡
donated a large portion of it to rebuild his hometown --
也就是害他父母丧命的地震
the one that was destroyed
所摧毁的家乡
in the earthquake that killed his parents.
你要试图把那笔钱追回来吗
Are you gonna try to recover it?
一旦资金出了国境
Well, it's very difficult to reclaim funds
就很难在追讨回来了
once they've left the country.
还不如用我们的资源去干点别的事呢
Think that we have better uses for our resources.
我该走了  再次感谢你们
I should be going, but thank you again.
那波曼呢  你还能对他立案吗
What about Berman? Do you still have a case?
虽说这跟我预想的结果不同
Well, not the one that I thought,
但起码我不至于在法庭上
but at least I won't embarrass myself in court
出示不真实证据令自己难堪了
presenting evidence that's untrue.
看来波曼白白损失了两千五百万美金
Then Berman paid $25 million for nothing.
这滋味肯定不好受呀
Bet that hurt.
或许吧  但这还不够
Probably, but it's not enough.
我们会正规地立案
We will build our case the right way.
也许要花上点时间  但我们会抓到他的
It may take some time, but we'll get him.
谢谢你  维多利亚
Thank you, Victoria.
谢我什么
For what?
谢谢你如此出色的工作
For doing your job so well.
我知道  现在已经不早了
So, I know it's -- it's late
你也许也想回家了
and you probably want to get home,
可是今天经历了这么多事  我真的很想和我的姐姐
but after today, I could really use a drink...
喝上一杯
...and a sister.
我也是
Me too.
到头来  盖茨的妹妹人也不坏嘛
You know, in the end, Gates' sister wasn't that bad.
这是不是意味着我们要请她来参加婚礼呢
Does that mean we have to invite her to the wedding?
对了  说起这件事  咱们的名单怎么办
Yeah, what about that -- our lists?
卡塞尔  我们不能请那么多人
Castle, we can't have that many people coming.
同意  那我们该怎么办呢
Agreed. So, what do we do?
我想我们必须决定
I think we have to decide
咱们到底为什么要办这场婚礼
why we're actually having this wedding.
我们办婚礼到底是为了
I mean, are we doing this
不伤害周围这几百人的感情呢
not to insult hundreds of people
还是为了咱们自己呢
or are we doing this for us?
当然是为了咱们自己
Well, for us.
那我们何不花上一分钟时间
Well, then, why don't we just take a minute
写下那些不管怎样都一定必须
and write down the names of all the people
要出席婚礼
that absolutely, positively have to be there,
就为了让咱俩开心的人的名单呢
no matter what, to make us happy?
就一分钟
One minute.
没错
Yeah.
时间很短啊  要是我们把某个人给忘了呢
That's not much time. What if we forget someone?
那就说明我们本来就不该请这个人
Then they shouldn't have been invited in the first place.
那就这么办吧
Let's do it.
好的
Okay.
好嘞
All right.
-准备好了吗  -准备好了
- Are we ready? - Yep.
一分钟
One minute.
计时开始
And go.
你停笔了
You stopped writing.
你也是
So did you.
当然了
Of course...
我必须要请我妈和阿丽克西
I'm going to have to invite my mother and Alexis.
-没错  还有我爸和特丽萨姑姑  -好的
- Yeah, and my dad and Aunt Theresa. - Right.
埃斯波和莱恩  莱恩肯定会带上珍妮
Espo and Ryan, who will bring Jenny.
还有蕾妮
Lanie.
蕾妮
我还得请一起打扑克那些人
I'm gonna have to invite the poker group.
-没错  麦迪  -盖茨
Yeah, Maddie. Gates.
还有盖茨的家人
Ooh! And Gates' family.